[音乐]
[MUSIC]
&gt；&gt；Kyle：所以我们要做练习1，好的。
&gt;&gt; Kyle: So we're gonna do Exercise 1 okay.
现在让我引导你们练习1和
Now let me orient you to Exercise 1 and
你现在得到这个方向是非常重要的。
it's really important you get this orientation solid right now.
因为我们要从头到尾重温这个练习，一直到七，一，
Because we are going to revisit this same exercise all the way through seven, one,
二，三，四，五，六，七是完全相同的问题域。
two, three, four, five, six, seven is the exact same problem domain.
以不同的异步模式重新访问，因此从练习1开始。
Revisited in different asynchronous patterns so starting out with Exercise 1.
让我们打开ex1.js中的read me。
Let's open up the Read Me in the ex1.js.
让我们试着更加熟悉这个练习要求我们做什么。
Let's try to get more familiar with what this exercise is asking us to do.
老实说，它要求我们做的是我试图表达一个漂亮的
And honestly what it's asking us to do is I've attempted to articulate a pretty
我们遇到的常见模式，特别是在系统的用户界面中。
common pattern that we run into especially in the user interface of our systems.
你要做的是协调
What you're going to be asked to do is coordinate
对一组虚假Ajax调用的响应。
the responses to a set of fake AJAX calls.
伪造Ajax调用，因为我不想让您担心设置自己的服务器或
Fake AJAX calls cuz I don't want you to worry about setting up your own servers or
任何东西，所以它会假装做Ajax。
any of the stuff so it's gonna pretend to do AJAX.
我在那里有随机的延迟，所以每次你运行你的程序
And I've got random delays in there such that every time you run your program
你会从中得到不同的行为。
you're gonna get different behavior out of it.
就像你在现实世界里一样，好吗？
Just like you would in the real world, okay?
但这些都是假的AJAX，它们实际上并不是在进行网络呼叫，但是
But these are fake AJAX they're not actually making network calls but
实际上这对我们来说是不是假的并不重要。
it actually doesn't matter to us whether it's fake.
对我们来说重要的是我们想假装我们在打电话
What matters to us is that we want to pretend as if we're making calls and
以相同的方式响应序列。
respond to the sequence of responses in a same way.
我们想要回应的方式是我们会要求所有三个人
And the way we want to respond to that is we're going to request all three of them
同时又是平行的。
at the same time aka in parallel.
我们知道我们真的应该使用并发这个词，但是
We know we really should use the term concurrent but
同时我们想在同一时间做出同样的三个反应，好的，
in parallel we want to make the same three responses at the same time, all right,
同样通过请求，同时。
same through request, at the same time.
现在，当我们从file1获得响应时，我们希望立即打印它。
Now, when we get a response back from file1 we want to print it right away.
事实上，如果我们得到了file1和file2，但file3仍在等待，
In fact, if we get file1 and file2 back, but file3 is still waiting,
我们希望立即打印file1和file2。
we want to print file1 and file2 right away.
我们想尽快提交，为什么？
We want to render them as soon as possible, why?
用户对性能的感知。
User perception of performance.
如果我们一直等到，我们在印刷之前就回来了，
If we waited until all through, we were back before we printed them,
用户会感觉到系统变慢了。
the user is going to feel like the system is slower.
但是如果我们循序渐进地跑或者不管我们有什么，他们会觉得
But if we progressively run or whatever we have they're going to feel like it's
更快，这是体验用户感知的一个非常重要的组成部分。
faster that's a really important component of experiences user perception.
即使花费相同的时间，感知也是重要的，但是
Even if it takes the same amount of time the perception is important but
一条额外的皱纹，
one additional wrinkle,
也就是说，我想确保这些文件按正确的顺序打印。
which is I want to make sure that those files print in the correct order.
因此，如果我File2立即返回并且
So if I file2 comes back right away and
File1仍处于挂起状态，请不要打印File2。
file1 is still pending, don't print file2 yet.
等到file1到达那里，然后打印这两个文件。
Wait until file1 gets there, and then print both of them.
所以我们想要做的就是尽快按正确的顺序渲染。
So what we're wanting to do is render ASAP but in the proper order.
你看，这里有一点扭曲，这是故意的
You see, there's a little bit of a twist here and that's intentional and
这是对用户界面设计中一种非常常见的模式的概括陈述。
that's a generalized statement of a pretty common pattern in user interface design.
并行地做多件事，
Doing multiple things in parallel,
等待他们回来，协调他们的反应，
waiting for them to come back, coordinating their responses,
尽快做出反应，但要确保事情按照相同的顺序发生。
responding as soon as possible but making sure things happen in a same order.
这就是这个练习要求你做的。
That's what this exercise calls for you to do.
因此，让我将您定向到ex1.js。
So let me orient you to ex1.js.
你注意到我有我的假AJAX，它是从
You notice I have my fake AJAX, it's mapping from
URL喜欢文件一到一些内容，我在那里有一些随机延迟。
URL like file one to some contents and I've got some random delay in there.
我有一个输出实用程序，它是控制台上的一个方便的包装器
I've got an output utility which is a convenient wrapper on the console along
供你使用。
for you to use.
这是我的getFile函数，它进行虚假的Ajax调用和
Here's my getFile function it makes that fake AJAX call and
这是你需要开始弄清楚一些代码的地方，因为
this is the part where you need to start figuring out some code because
并行调用getFile三次非常容易。
it's pretty easy to call getFile three times in parallel.
我免费提供给你，但问题不是如何协调请求。
I gave you that for free but the question is not how to coordinate the requests.
问题是
The question is,
我如何正确地协调回应，这里有一些提示给你。
how do I properly coordinate the responses and here is some hints for you.
你会得到响应，因为随机线程可以
You're gonna have responses coming back, because the randomized threads you can
让他们按任何特定的顺序回来。
have them come back in any particular order.
他们中的一些人可能回来得太早了。
Some of them might come back too early.
这意味着我们需要一些东西来保持
Which means we're going to need to have something hold onto
一些国家的一段时间。
some state for a while.
您需要某种全局变量或对象或数组或
You need some sort of global variable or object or array or
如果你还没有准备好打印这些回复，你可以拿着它们。
something to hold on the responses in case you're not ready to print them.
你需要弄清楚所有这些共享的回调或者
And you need to figure out of all all these callbacks sharing over that or
协调该共享状态和
coordinating over that shared state and
弄清楚什么时候可以打印一些东西，并且只打印一次。
figuring out when it's okay to print something and only printing it once.
好的，所以我们将采取大约我说的五个，我们将
All right, so we're going to take about I said five, we'll
花十分钟，因为我想确保每个人都在玩这个。
take ten minutes because I wanna make sure everybody plays around with this.
我们会花十分钟，然后下午休息一下
We'll take the ten minutes and then we are gonna take an afternoon break
过了十分钟，我们会回来的。
after the ten minutes, so we will come back.
讨论解决方案并
Talk through the solution and
那就是我们下午休息的时间了。
then that will be the time that we take our afternoon break.
但如果你愿意，我想让你玩弄一下回拨的痛苦
But I want you to play around with the pain of callbacks if you will
通过理解做应该是一种简单用例的事情有多难。
by understanding just how hard it is to do what should be sort of a simple use case.
当你必须自己管理所有状态时，这实际上是相当困难的
It's actually pretty difficult when you have to manage all that state yourself
通过回拨。
through callbacks.